<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cincinnati Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="welcome_text">Welcome to Cincinnati, the Queen city.</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close</string>
    <string name="main_category_things_to_do">Things To Do</string>
    <string name="main_category_landmarks">Landmarks To See</string>
    <string name="main_category_eat">Eat &amp; Drink</string>
    <string name="main_category_city_history">City History</string>
    <string name="seeMore">See More</string>
    <string name="rates_header"><u>Rates:</u></string>
    <string name="hours_header"><u>Hours:</u></string>

    <string name="history_header_early_history">Early history</string>
    <string name="history_early_history">Cincinnati was founded in late December 1788 by Mathias Denman, Colonel Robert Patterson and Israel Ludlow. The original surveyor, John Filson, named it \"Losantiville\", from four terms, each of different language, before his death in October 1788. It means \"The city opposite the mouth of the (Licking) River\", \"ville\" is French for \"city\", \"anti\" is Greek for \"opposite\", \"os\" is Latin for \"mouth\", and \"L\" was all that was included of \"Licking River\".\n\nCincinnati began as three settlements between the Little Miami and Great Miami rivers on the north shore of the Ohio River. Columbia was on the Little Miami, North Bend on the Great Miami. Losantiville, the central settlement, was opposite the mouth of the Licking River.\n\nIn 1789 Fort Washington was built to protect the settlements in the Northwest Territory.\n\nIn 1790, Arthur St. Clair, the governor of the Northwest Territory, changed the name of the settlement to \"Cincinnati\" in honor of the Society of the Cincinnati, of which he was president. The society gets its name from Cincinnatus, the Roman general and dictator, who saved the city of Rome from destruction and then quietly retired to his farm. The society honored the ideal of return to civilian life by military officers following the Revolution rather than imposing military rule. To this day, Cincinnati in particular, and Ohio in general, is home to a disproportionately large number of descendants of Revolutionary War soldiers who were granted lands in the state. Cincinnati\'s connection with Rome still exists today through its nickname of \"The City of Seven Hills\" (a phrase commonly associated with Rome) and the town twinning program of Sister Cities International.\n\nCincinnati was chartered as a town on January 1, 1802.  It was chartered as a city by an act of the General Assembly that passed February 5, 1819, and took effect on March 1 of that year. The introduction of steam navigation on the Ohio River in 1811 and the completion of the Miami and Erie Canal helped the city grow to 115,000 citizens by 1850. Cincinnati was an important stop on the Underground Railroad, which helped slaves escape from the South.\n\nCincinnati was the site of many historical beginnings. In 1850 it was the first city in the United States to establish a Jewish Hospital. It is where America\'s first municipal fire department, the Cincinnati Fire Department, was established in 1853. Cincinnati was the first municipality to build and own a major railroad in 1880. In 1902, the world\'s first re-inforced concrete skyscraper was built, the Ingalls Building.\n\nDuring the first forty years after its founding, Cincinnati experienced spectacular growth. By 1820, citizens, extremely proud of their city, were referring to it as The Queen City or The Queen of the West.</string>

    <string name="history_header_civil_war">Civil War</string>
    <string name="history_civil_war">During the American Civil War, Cincinnati played a key role as a major source of supplies and troops for the Union Army. Cincinnati served as a major recruiting and organization center for the United States military during the Civil War. The city\'s businesses thrived, as they provided supplies for the soldiers and housing for both the soldiers and their families. Most residents of Cincinnati supported the United States, but a sizable number of people went south to fight for the Confederacy.</string>

    <string name="history_header_underground_railroad">Underground Railroad</string>
    <string name="history_underground_railroad">Cincinnati was an important stop for the Underground Railroad in pre-Civil War times. It bordered a slave state, Kentucky, and is often mentioned as a destination for many people escaping the bonds of slavery. There are many harrowing stories involving abolitionists, runaways, slave traders and free men. The National Underground Railroad Freedom Center, located in downtown Cincinnati on the banks of the Ohio River, largely focuses on the history of slavery in the U.S., but has an underlying mission of promoting freedom in a contemporary fashion for the world. Its grand opening ceremony in 2002 was a gala event involving many national stars, musical acts, fireworks, and a visit from the current First Lady of the United States. It is physically located between Great American Ballpark and Paul Brown Stadium, which were both built and opened shortly before the Freedom Center was opened.</string>

    <string name="history_header_sports">Sports</string>
    <string name="history_sports">Established in 1867, the Cincinnati Red Stockings (a.k.a. the Cincinnati Reds) became the world\'s first professional (all paid, no amateurs) baseball team in 1869. In 1935, major league baseball\'s first night game was played at Crosley Field. The Cincinnati Bengals football team of the NFL was founded in 1968 by legendary coach Paul Brown. The team appeared in the 1981 and 1988 Super Bowls. FC Cincinnati, Cincinnati\'s professional soccer team of the United Soccer League, was founded in 2015. While currently in a division II league, the club has received international recognition for its consistent record-breaking attendance numbers and historic 2017 Lamar Hunt U.S. Open Cup run. The team has been granted a spot in Major League Soccer for their 2019 expansion.</string>

    <string name="history_header_fountain">Tyler Davidson Fountain</string>
    <string name="history_fountain">On October 6, 1871, Henry Probasco presented the fountain to the people of Cincinnati as a memorial to his brother-in-law, Tyler Davidson. Cast by Ferdinand von Muller, Director of the Royal Bronze Foundry of Bavaria, the fountain followed plans drawn by August von Kreling. The 9-foot central figure, the Genius of Water, stands with arms outstretched over groupings of figures representing the uses of water.</string>

    <string name="history_header_disasters">Disasters</string>
    <string name="history_disasters">On December 3, 1979 11 persons were killed in a crowd crush at the entrance of Riverfront Coliseum for a rock concert by the British band The Who.\n\nCincinnati has experienced multiple floods in its history. The largest being the Ohio River flood of 1937 where Cincinnati measured flood waters at 80 feet.\n\nOhio was just one of many states that suffered from the third deadliest tornado swarm in the United States, which consisted of 47 tornados in less than 12 hours known as the 1965 Palm Sunday Tornado Outbreak.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

</resources>
